AUSTIN KAMMERER

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

austin4191@gmail.com | github.com/AustinKammerer | (970)-660-7169

SUMMARY

Finding the solution to a problem, whether it's a full stack coding project, a jigsaw puzzle, or navigating an expert level big-mountain ski run, is what gives me purpose. I aim to challenge my mind and to improve the well-being of myself and those around me. Giving back and passing knowledge to others is important to me, as I believe it should be accessible to everyone. When prioritizing diversity, equity, and inclusion, I believe workplaces will be empowered to positively affect the world around them.

SKILLS

HTML CSS JavaScript C# Material UI Bootstrap React.js React Router Redux Saga AJAX jQuery Node.js Express.js Passport.js Entity Framework SQL Postgres AWS-S3 Web APIs Git

EXPERIENCE

Prime Digital Academy | Minneapolis, MN | August 2021 – Present

Full Stack Software Engineering Student

Client Project - Lyster (in development)

- Developing a React marketplace application to allows users to rent recreational vehicles from each other
- Working closely with the client to understand their needs and develop the best possible solution
- Technologies used: Material UI, JavaScript, React, React Router, Redux, Saga, AJAX, Node, Express, Passport, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Services (S3), OpenStreetMap

Solo Project - Parks Passport

- Developed a React application to allow users to easily search for National Parks and record their trips
- Utilizes the National Park Service API to gather and display information for the user in a convenient way
- Allows users to upload photos they take during park visits using Amazon's S3 cloud service
- Technologies used: Material UI, JavaScript, React, React Router, Redux, Saga, AJAX, Node, Express, Passport, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Services (S3)

Hilco Maintenance | Silverthorne, CO | October 2020 – May 2021

Plow Driver & Shop Worker

- Maintained flexibility around weather conditions and met clients' snow removal needs
- Coordinated with the owner, supervisor, and other drivers to efficiently complete snow removal routes
- Maintained and repaired snow removal equipment and vehicles to ensure reliability during peak operations

Arapahoe Basin Ski Area | Colorado | January 2014 – June 2020

Base Area Assistant Manager | January 2019 - June 2020

- Responsible for leading, training, and scheduling up to twenty Base Area staff, including leads, attendants, shuttle drivers, and heavy equipment operators, and managed employee payroll
- ❖ Improved the new Base Area employee onboarding experience by developing a new training program
- Participated in the company's Leadership Development Program and several Employer's Council leadership courses
- Provided service for a diverse client base and ensured a positive arrival experience for ski area guests and employees
- Supervised and coordinated parking, shuttle buses, and plowing in order to maximize parking space and revenue

Snow Removal Supervisor | November 2017 - January 2019

- Developed and coordinated daily snow removal plans for the ski area's parking lots and public areas
- Communicated needs to the Plow Driver department and staffed shifts accordingly to meet the ski area's parking lot expectations

Snowmaker | September 2016 - November 2018

- Operated snowmaking equipment in variable conditions to ensure the earliest possible opening date
- Communicated needs and developed plans with the Grooming and Ski Patrol departments

Summer Trail Crew | June 2017 - September 2018

- Provided leadership, executed projects without supervision, and communicated progress with supervisors
- Constructed snow retention fences and signage in the Beavers & Steep Gullies expansion

Base Area Lead | November 2016 - June 2017

- Communicated the manager's needs and delegated tasks to a diverse group of employees
- Operated various equipment and vehicles including skid-steer, front loader, and passenger shuttles
- Provided excellent guest service and support for various events at the ski area

Lift Operator | January 2014 - May 2016

- ❖ Interacted with the ski area's guests and loaded them safely and comfortably onto aerial ski lifts
- Checked guests' tickets and prevented the loss of thousands of dollars of revenue due to ticket problems

The University of Iowa Institute for Rural and Environmental Health | June 2012 – December 2013 Chemistry Research Assistant

- Worked with a diverse term of researchers to develop standard operating procedures and methods for a grant-based research project
- Performed incubations of animal liver microsomes and lipid extractions of major organs to study the metabolism of polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs), an environmental contaminant
- Operated a range of laboratory equipment including high-tech scientific instruments (GC, GC-MS, ASE)
- Collected, analyzed, and prepared data using Agilent OpenLab and Microsoft Excel for a publication in a scientific journal

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy | Minneapolis, MN | Expected Graduation: January 2022

Full Stack Software Engineering Certificate

Prime Digital Academy is a full-time software development immersion program. It also focuses on professional skills development, public speaking, diversity equity and inclusion, and real-world client work.

The University of Iowa | Iowa City, IA | Graduated 2013

Bachelor of Science - Environmental Science, Chemistry Minor

Publication:

Wu, Xianai, et al. "Microsomal Oxidation of 2,2',3,3',6,6'-Hexachlorobiphenyl (PCB 136) Results in Species-Dependent Chiral Signatures of the Hydroxylated Metabolites." *Environmental Science & Technology*, vol. 48, no. 4, 2014, pp. 2436–44. *Crossref*, doi:10.1021/es405433t.